PREVIOUSLY ON TATSUKI: TOO KIND FOR SCHOOL
It's pointless if it's not perfect.
Why did you make a mistake?
You want to win the gold medal, right?
I think there's a possibility
that Umine is being subjected
to "tiger parenting."
When I see Umine,
I'm reminded of myself
when I was a child.
So I feel the need to do something.
I understand how you feel,
but you should step back.
Then who is going to
look after her instead?
Who'll listen to her cries for help?
Calm down.
Take some time off work.
All I did was hurt you. I'm really sorry.
What's the matter?
She barricaded herself inside.
What?
Umine, come on out.
Call Daddy.
What?
Call Tatsuki.
Sorry, I have to go.
-You didn't used to be like this.
-What?
You never helped me when I needed it.
You need to go, right?
Sorry, I'll contact you later.
Tatsuki's here.
-Where've you been?
-Hey there.
-Welcome back.
-Mr. Tatsuki.
Where's Umine?
She locked herself in the room.
Umine.
Sorry.
Can you let me come inside?
What's the matter?
You broke your promise.
You said you'd be by my side
no matter what.
Sorry, I had family matters to attend to.
I was being good, you know.
Want to do something? How about drawing?
No.
I have homework for cram school.
We'll be going now.
-Bye.
-Bye. Stay safe.
-Hello.
Hello.
I'll go call Umine.
Thank you.
Umine, your dad is here.
You can stay longer, if you want.
Mr. Tatsuki.
I'll go.
Do you think Tatsuki is all right?
I wonder.
Um…
I'll be leaving now.
What will you be…?
Oh.
I was told to take time off work,
but I have nowhere else to go.
Can I stay here?
I'm sure that's okay.
Sorry.
Then, I'll be going now.
YUKANAI
COUNTERTRANSFERENCE
TATSUKI IS RESTING
Good morning.
We have to start getting ready
for the middle school graduation party.
You're right.
This year, Tomoki and Tonetaku
are graduating.
I see.
UMINE
I HAVE TO STUDY AGAIN…
IF YOU CAN'T HANDLE IT…
If you lose your head over this,
you won't be able to save her.
Kae, you're good at this.
-Really?
-Yeah.
How can I make it into a triangle?
Curve your hand like this,
and rotate it like this.
But it'll turn into a round ball.
No way.
Is Tatsuki not feeling well?
Seems like it. We should let him rest.
I guess I'll be nice
and deliver a rice ball.
Good idea.
I bet Tatsuki is hungry.
But isn't the door locked?
TATSUKI IS RESTING
Then…
Can Kae and Sakurako take it to him?
Rice balls, rice balls.
Would you like some
freshly made rice balls?
Thank you.
Tatsuki, are you not feeling well?
Just a little. But no worries.
This one is salted kelp,
but guess what flavor
the other one is.
What could it be?
Is it bonito flakes?
Eat it and you'll find out.
Okay,
then I'll try it.
-How is it?
-Is it good?
It's strawberry!
But it's actually not that bad.
Thank you for your business.
Please excuse us.
Thank you.
-Can I come in?
-Yeah.
I told you to take time off work,
but you don't have
anywhere else to go, huh?
Yeah, sorry.
It seems like Umine will also be taking
some time off for the math competition.
I see.
I wonder if Umine is doing all right.
I wonder.
Why are you so worried about Umine?
I don't know why.
But whenever I see Umine,
memories of my own childhood
cross my mind.
What is it guys?
All right.
-You guys can come in now.
-Tatsuki.
-How are you doing?
-Tatsuki, are you all right?
-Yeah, I'm all right.
Okay, let's all draw together!
-Yeah!
-Hooray!
What are we drawing?
Anything we want?
Should we use the new paint?
-Good idea.
-Then
let's draw a nostalgic scene
from your childhood.
I'm still a child.
You're right.
Then from when you were really little.
Do you remember anything?
I have to think about it.
Tatsuki, you should draw too.
What?
Scenery I saw when I was little?
Scenery that remains
in your memory even now.
Okay.
I'm always impressed
by your drawing skills, Tatsuki.
Were you always good at it?
I'm not sure.
But I always loved to draw.
What's the matter?
It's nothing.
All right, how about we step outside
for a change of pace.
Get in.
Okay.
Where are we going?
I haven't decided.
We'll go where the wind takes us.
So you got to talk with Sora, huh?
Yes.
But I've done some pretty awful things…
So when I had to rush back to Yukanai
for Umine,
he told me,
"You didn't used to be like this."
And he said, "You never helped me
when I needed it."
I was at a loss for words.
Well, it looks like it's going to take
a little more time
before your feelings get across to him.
So why did you stop drawing
halfway through?
For a moment, I was reminded of a moment
in my childhood.
I have a memory of drawing a vivid,
fiery-red sky for a school assignment
or something.
Though, come to think of it,
it's probably not a fond memory.
I see.
What were you like as a kid?
I was relatively quiet,
and studied pretty diligently.
My father was big on education,
so he was quite strict.
How is your relationship
with your dad now?
We don't really talk much,
but I'd say it's pretty normal.
I see.
Then I guess it's okay.
What's okay?
-Let's go to your parents' house.
-What?
Now?
Put the address in the GPS.
Are you serious?
COUNTERTRANSFERENCE
You're studying something?
Umine calls Mr. Tatsuki "Daddy,"
and directs the kind of feelings
one holds for a parent toward him.
Yeah.
According to Professor Mikuko,
that's called transference.
And Mr. Tatsuki was also
deeply invested emotionally
when it concerned Umine, right?
Oh, that's called countertransference?
Right.
I mean, it doesn't necessarily mean
that it's a bad thing, though.
That's what you're studying?
I was wondering
if there was anything I could do
while Mr. Tatsuki is taking a break.
Oh, speaking of, tomorrow is Umine's
mathematics competition, isn't it?
Yeah.
NATIONAL MATHEMATICS COMPETITION
"THAT'S RIGHT" MOCK EXAM
Come in.
-Hey.
-Tatsuki, what a surprise.
This is Mr. Mikumo from my workplace.
-Hello.
Please come inside.
Oh my.
Hey, dear.
What's with that hair?
That's my dad.
Hello, nice to meet you.
I'm Mikumo, the representative
at an alternative school called Yukanai.
-Thank you for helping out my son.
-Not at all.
I really was just passing by,
so I’ll be taking my leave now.
Hold on.
I'll come back to pick you up.
So rest well.
-You've got to be kidding.
-Please stay and eat with us.
-Thank you, but please don't mind me.
-Don't leave me.
Come over here, dear.
Please stay for a while.
You have to listen to my dad.
Fine.
Thank you for your kind offer.
Would you like to take a bath?
I'm fine, thank you.
AWARD CERTIFICATE
All right, so what do you think
the protagonist is feeling
-in this scene?
-I know!
Me!
Okay, Koike.
She's feeling sad.
That's correct.
Yes, Ukita?
Is that really the correct answer?
What?
It might not just be sadness.
There might also be feelings of relief.
-But the husband died…
-Or she might be spaced out.
But she lost someone very dear to her…
Is there really only one answer?
That's enough.
For your art homework,
please draw a picture
of your favorite type of sky, okay?
Yes.
-I'll draw a whale-shaped cloud.
-Nice.
What are you drawing?
It's my homework. I'm drawing the sky.
Why is it red?
That doesn't look like a sky.
Draw it properly.
‎What?
Stop messing around,
and draw it properly
so that it actually looks like a sky.
Got it?
Yes.
Ukita's artwork
was selected for the city art contest!
Let's hear it for him!
-Wow!
-You're amazing!
Come up here, Ukita.
-Yes.
-You're the best!
Congratulations.
Show it to everyone.
Let's give him a round of applause.
Wow!
See? I was right, wasn't I?
It really was the right call to redraw it.
You're amazing, Tatsuki.
Which university are you applying for?
After I graduate high school,
I want to study art.
I want to go to a vocational school
specializing in arts.
A vocational school?
What you want to study
is up to you to decide,
so just do whatever you like.
But you have to go to university.
What?
You might not be able
to make a living from art.
Wouldn't going to university
broaden your options?
Is that really so?
Go to university.
Your grades aren't bad, after all.
Hey, where's my sketchbook?
It was creating a mess,
so I put it out with the recyclables.
What? Why?
I told you to clean up so many times,
but you never got around to it.
Why did you throw it away?
Don't get so angry with me.
You don't need it for the entrance exams.
This was your room?
Yeah, although it's being used
as a storage room now.
You held on to your work, huh?
Look at this.
Dad told me that this doesn't look
like a drawing of the sky.
So I redrew it, and here it is.
I see.
When I did what my dad told me to do,
I ended up winning an award.
From then on, all focus turned
to winning awards.
Even though
I came to love drawing because
it allowed me to express myself freely.
I see.
I think the reason why I can't stop
being concerned about Umine
is because her situation
is similar to my own childhood.
I worry
that she's suffering from the pressure
to produce good results.
You might be right.
I wonder what kind of feelings
you dad had toward you back then.
My dad's feelings?
Is Sora doing well?
You still see him?
I saw him recently.
I see.
We were worried about
how things have been since the divorce.
You fish?
Yeah, you didn't know?
I never saw him fishing.
Well, he was always buried in work.
But now he has the time.
Wanna go together?
No, thanks.
It's fun.
Go take a bath.
Okay.
I didn't know that fishing was your hobby.
I started after I retired.
I thought you weren't the type
who could sit still like this.
Yeah, now that you mention it.
I guess you changed.
Probably.
When I was a kid
I won an award
for drawing a picture of a blue sky.
Do you remember?
A drawing of a blue sky?
I don't remember.
I figured.
But I remember you were good at drawing.
Why do you bring that up?
At first, I had drawn a red sky,
but I was forced to redraw it.
By whom?
You.
Why would I do that?
You said that a red sky was unrealistic
and told me to redraw a blue sky.
-I said that?
-Yes, you, Dad.
You don't remember it at all?
I mean, a red sky would've been just fine.
Right?
That always bothered me.
I always wondered
why the sky had to be blue.
Yeah, why is that?
That's what I want to know!
You should have just done
whatever you wanted.
That wasn't the vibe at all back then.
Not at all.
I see…
I guess your mom and I
were just desperate to keep you
from straying off the path
and to prevent you from failing.
Are you still holding a grudge
against me for that?
No.
You guys put me through university,
and I was able to find a job.
A lot happened since then,
but it led me to where I am now.
I'm glad.
But
I did to Sora the exact same thing
you did to me.
‎What?
To ensure he wouldn't stray from the path
and to prevent him from failing,
I forced my own values upon him…
and drove Sora into a corner.
That's
not good.
Although I don't want to
hear that from you.
Was I really
-that kind of a parent?
-Huh?
Was I really the type
to micromanage your life?
Yes, I never had a say in anything.
Is that right?
Yeah.
I have no recollection of that at all.
You better not forget it anymore.
NATIONAL MATHEMATICS COMPETITION
I'll go in now.
Don't rush, and stay calm.
Go get the gold medal.
I'll do my best.
I wonder how Umine is doing
at her mathematics competition.
Yeah, I wonder.
I want her to do her best, but…
Yeah.
I wonder if she'll be back
starting tomorrow.
I hope so.
I hope she doesn't end up
clinging on to Tatsuki again.
Apparently,
one way to prevent that from happening
is to distribute the interactions
she has with people.
Distribute?
It's important to reduce the time
she spends alone with Mr. Tatsuki,
and all of us need to start
interacting with her as well.
The idea is to "spread out
and diversify the support system."
So, basically, all of us should
rally around Umine.
That's right.
-Good morning.
What are we doing for
the graduation party performance?
We haven't talked to you guys about it.
What do you want to do?
I want to put on a puppet show.
-That's a good idea.
-Yeah.
Can we join you guys too?
-Of course.
Shi-chan and Ajicchan,
-you guys can borrow my stuffed toys.
-Thank you.
Do I get to play a role too?
Let's see…
-You can be Muscle Man.
-Muscle Man!
I won't be using a doll then?
Just your arms.
Were you able to talk with your dad?
Yes.
How did it go?
It turns out
he doesn't remember any of that stuff
he did in the past at all.
He was so unbothered by it,
it was anticlimactic.
That's awesome.
It's not funny.
I guess it just goes to show that
even parents aren't perfect.
Yeah.
I gave a lot of thought regarding
Umine and Sora.
Is that right?
There's something I want to tell Umine.
Is it okay if I return to Yukanai?
Okay.
I'll pick you up.
Thank you.
-Okay.
-That's good.
-Where to next?
-Right.
-Right?
-No, left.
Hello.
Long time no see, Umine.
It's been a while, Shi-chan.
It's been a while.
What do you want to do?
Want to make takoyaki? Or popcorn?
Let's do whatever you feel like.
-Hey everyone, we're back.
-We're back.
It's Tatsuki!
-Tatsuki, you're back!
-Welcome back.
-You're okay now?
-Yup.
Did you bring gifts?
Sorry, I don't have any.
That's too bad.
Welcome back.
Thanks for all your help.
It was no problem.
Umine is here.
Look at this.
AWARD CERTIFICATE
MISS UMINE ANDO
I got third place.
You won third place? Congratulations!
I ran out of time
and messed up at the end.
She tried,
but she fell just short of the goal.
Winning a bronze medal is an amazing feat.
Oh, I guess so.
Hey everyone, attention please!
What is it?
We're going to do button art now!
Wow, look at all those buttons.
There are plenty of buttons,
so feel free to use as many as you like.
Umine, want to try button art again?
-Yeah.
-Okay.
All right, go ahead
and use the buttons however you like
to express whatever you want!
Okay!
This is crazy.
What should I make?
What do you like, Umine?
Math?
Right now
I don't like it that much.
What did you like about math?
When I was little,
around your age, I loved to draw.
That was because
it allowed me to express myself freely.
I wonder why I fell in love with math?
Now that you’ve finished making it,
how do you feel?
When doing math
I liked getting
the flashes of inspiration.
That's what made me fall in love with it.
I see.
But I wonder why…
I wonder why I stopped loving it.
All right everyone,
you can display your artwork
wherever you like.
Okay.
Let's display ours together.
-You can display it wherever you want.
-Umine!
Do you want to join our puppet show
at the graduation party?
You haven't been able to play at all
because of the math competition, right?
Here.
She wants to give it back to you.
You're a big girl now,
so you don't need this, right?
I…
sold this already.
But it's yours, Umine.
MIDDLE SCHOOL GRADUATION PARTY
See you again, see you again
No need to feel lonely anymore
I'll always be here waiting for you
It's okay, you can do it
All right,
let's begin
the middle school graduation party.
To kick things off,
let's hear from the two students
graduating from middle school this year.
Let's hear it for Takumi.
Hey.
I'm Tonetaku,
Yukanai's charismatic figure!
That's hilarious.
Who said you're charismatic?
Please keep it short.
I didn't attend middle school at all,
so Yukanai is what I consider
my middle school.
The precious time I spent here
with everyone
was very…
How should I say it…?
-You're crying?
-Is he okay?
-He's really crying?
-Really?
Psyche!
You totally got me.
Sorry, guys.
Let's continue being friends from now on.
I love all of you.
-Give me a high-five.
-Okay.
Yeah!
Thank you.
Next up is Tomoki.
If…
I hadn't met Tatsuki and Shi-chan,
I might not even be alive right now.
So I'm very grateful.
Thank you.
You're going to make me cry.
-Thank you, Tomoki!
-You're so cool, Tomoki.
Someday,
I’m going to become
the world’s number one esports player,
become filthy rich,
and blow everyone’s minds!
That's awesome.
Well, even after they graduate
middle school,
they can drop by Yukanai
whenever they want,
so let's all hang out again!
And now, onto the puppet show
"The Adventures
of the Witches Riri and Ruru."
Ready?
Let's begin!
If you want to go any further,
you must solve the question
I'm going to give you.
Oh no! Everyone, help us figure it out.
Okay, let's begin.
A notebook and an eraser
cost 110 yen altogether.
The notebook is 100 yen more expensive
than the eraser.
Then
how much does the eraser cost?
-Isn't it ten yen?
-Yeah, ten yen.
-Oh yeah?
-It's really ten yen?
-Yeah, it's ten yen.
-Ten yen.
It's gotta be ten yen, right?
I got it!
-Your answer please!
-Five yen.
-Correct!
-Hooray!
It’s been a long time since I’ve seen her
look so happy.
Yeah.
The bridge opened up.
In the beginning,
whenever she was able to solve
a math problem,
she had the look of pure joy.
-I solved it.
-Correct.
All right!
That made me really happy too.
And I wanted
to give her even more reasons to smile.
What kind of a country are we in?
It is a country that cherishes
the things that you love.
The things that I love…
But somewhere along the way,
mathematics turned into
something painful for Umine.
I took away
something precious
that Umine loved.
Mr. Ando.
You and Umine
will be just fine.
Ruru, what do you want to do
in this country?
I'll think a lot.
-I'll play a lot.
-That's nice.
And
I'll wait for flashes of inspiration.
That's awesome.
How lovely.
That's the end of
"The Adventures
of the Witches Riri and Ruru."
Ready?
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Not at all.
I want to do some math quizzes
when I get home!
Okay, let's do it.
Bye, Tatsuki.
Until next time, Umine.
Let's go, Daddy.
All right, shall we clean up?
Yeah.
YU
13 MISSED CALLS
Please, stop.
Stop this, Sora.
-What the hell, damn it!
-Sora!
Hey.
What are you doing?
Shut up!
I wonder where we went wrong.
THIS DRAMA IS FICTIONAL
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita